# **SAGAR PANDEY**

## **Key Skills**

- SharePoint Online
- SharePoint OnPrem
- Azure PaaS
- Power Platform
- React

## **Technical Skills**

## Front End

- JavaScript
- **Typescript**
- React
- **iQuery**

### **Backend**

- .NET (C#)
- SQL
- Firebase
- Mongo
- ExpressJs

#### **Platforms**

- Azure
- SharePoint
- Microsoft365
- **Power Automate**
- **Power Apps**

## Tools

- Visual Studio
- Azure DevOps

## **Recent Certifications**

- **Azure Fundamentals** (AZ-900)
- M365 Fundamentals (MS900)
- M365 App Dev (MS600)
- MSCD/A App Builder

# Languages Known

- English
- Hindi
- Marathi

# Summary

Having 10+ years of experience in SharePoint Content and Document Management implementations.

Have been involved in analysing the needs of large systems and breaking them down into smaller manageable parts.

Plan and design the structure of technology systems, discuss these with the client Communicate best products and systems to client.

Communicate system requirements to software designers and developers, explain system structure to them and provide assistance throughout the assembly process.

## Work Experience

#### Technical Architect

**Hexaware Technologies** 

Feb' 2017 - Till date

- Worked alongside other architects to architect scalable SharePoint Online site provisioning engines using Serverless Concept (Azure Functions).
- Involved in designing and developing SPFx React based landing page for the accessible sites leveraging client-side caching.
- Designed Custom Scalable Workflows based on distributed database.
- Involved in Designing Power Platform implementations.
- Facilitating best practises and standards by enforcing lint and Checkmarx rules.
- Involved in providing suggestions to reduce cost based on App Insight reports.
- Proposed and implemented automation of deployment via CI/CD pipelines.

#### Associate

Cognizant Technologies

Aug 2014 - Feb 2017

- Worked on SharePoint 2013/SharePoint Online Platform, Azure Platform.
- Worked on an application using SharePoint 2013 as a Content management system and document management system with SharePoint Designer Workflows.
- Modernized the SharePoint sites by converting classic Farm based solutions to SHA, PHA Apps using CSOM based on the best fit of the solution.
- Developed Intranet Portal for client leveraging OOTB webparts and custom client-side script using JSOM and REST API

### Consultant

Datamatics Global Software Ltd

Feb 2013 - Aug 2014

- Developed Employee Onboarding System and Employee Appraisal System by integrating it with SAP in SP 2013.
- Developed Intranet Portal on SP 2010 platform leveraging SSOM.
- Redesigned Intranet portal to be Mobile responsive by eliminating rigid structure.

## Software Developer

AG Technologies

Dec 2010 - Feb 2013

- Developed Work Item management application for a manufacturing organization client leveraging SP 2013 for Workflows and Document Management.
- Worked on Proposal Management System on SP2010 using Server object model, Custom Web Services to connect SAP for Master data. Also leverage InfoPath forms for data capturing forms.

## **Educational Skills**

Bachelor's in engineering (Electronics) 2010